https://www.cotswoldoutdoor.com/legals/cookie-policy.html

Find Out More
If you have a general query, please check our Help Centre, which may be able to provide your answer. If you have a more specific question about our Privacy Policy, please contact us.
Information About Our Use Of Cookies
Cotswold Outdoor uses cookies and similar technologies to distinguish your usage preferences from those of other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a better user experience when you visit our website and allows us to optimise our website.
As a result of recent legislative changes, all websites targeting certain parts of the European Union are required to ask for your permission to use or store cookies and similar technologies on your computers or mobile devices. This cookie policy gives you clear and complete information about the cookies we use and their purpose. Please read our Privacy Policy to learn about the privacy rules that apply to the website.
Our use of Adobe Analytics cookies
Adobe technology is central to the operation of our web platforms. Because Adobe technology is critical to the operation of our website and we want to continue to guarantee you the best online experience, we currently consider Adobe Analytics cookies as functional cookies that support the operation of the website.
For further information about this Cookie Policy, you can contact us at customer.services@cotswoldoutdoor.com
What Is A Cookie?
A cookie is a small text and number file that we store in your browser or on the hard drive of your computer. That way we can remember your preferences when using our website.
As soon as you visit www.cotswoldoutdoor.com you will be asked for permission to place different categories of cookies that we use.
Types Of Cookies
Cookies can be divided according to their origin, their function and their lifespan.
First party cookies are those cookies that are placed by a website that is currently being visited by the user (eg cookies placed by www.cotswoldoutdoor.com).
Third-party cookies are cookies that are placed by a domain name other than that of the website visited by the user. If a user visits a website and a third party places a cookie via that website, this is a third-party cookie (eg cookies placed by Google, Twitter and Facebook).
Functional cookies are cookies that ensure that the website functions properly (eg cookies for log-in or registration, language preferences). Functional cookies are logically first party cookies.
Non-functional cookies are cookies that can be placed for statistical, social, targeting and commercial purposes. They have nothing to do with the purely technical support of the website. Cookies with static purposes allow to check which pages of the website you visit, where your computer is located, etc. Cookies with social purposes enable the user to share the content of the visited website directly with others via social media. Cookies with targeting purposes allow a profile to be built based on your surfing behavior so that the advertisements displayed are tailored to your interests. Cookies with commercial purposes keep track of how many and which advertisements were shown to a user. Non-functional cookies can be first party or third party cookies.
Permanent cookies: These cookies remain on the user's device for the duration specified in the cookie. They are activated every time the user visits the website that has placed this cookie (eg cookies placed by social media such as Twitter, Facebook, Google Analytics, etc.). Most non-functional cookies are permanent cookies.
Session cookies: These cookies allow us to simplify the actions of a user and to link them during a browser session. A browser session starts when a user opens the browser screen and ends when they close the browser screen. Session cookies are placed temporarily. As soon as you close the browser, all session cookies are deleted. Most functional cookies are session cookies.
Your Consent
By using our website, you accept the use of mandatory cookies. We have bundled the other types of cookies and tracking mechanisms into two groups: analytical cookies and marketing cookies. We only install these cookies if we have your permission. You can always change your cookie settings afterwards via the link to the cookie policy at the bottom of every page of the website.
Change Your Browser Settings
We point out that web browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. These settings can usually be found in the 'Options' or 'Preferences' menu of your web browser. To better understand these settings, the following links may be helpful. If not, you should consult the 'Help' function in your web browser for more details.
• Cookie settings in Internet Explorer
• Cookie settings Firefox
• Cookie settings in Chrome
• Cookie settings in Safari
Information about cookies
You can find useful information about cookies here:  http://www.allaboutcookies.org/
Internet Advertising Bureau
The interest group of digital marketers has drawn up a guide to online behavioural advertising and online privacy which you can find here: http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/
Functional Cookies
These cookies enable essential parts of the website and functions work properly, such as logging in or adding items to the shopping cart. This option is always enabled, otherwise you will not be able to view the Cotswold Outdoor website or shop online.
Name
Target
Properties
Cookie Name
Adobe Analytics
With Adobe Analytics we measure how you use our webshop and how you found us. We use this knowledge to improve our sites. Without these cookies, we will miss your data.
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 1 session.
Adobe does not share anonymous data with third parties.
s_cc, s_ppn, s_ppv, s_ppvl, s_sq, s_vi
AddThis
With AddThis articles can be shared on social networks
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 3 months
_cae
Zopim
We use these cookies to support our chat functionality
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 1 year
__cfduid, __zlcmid
YouTube
YouTube (Google) stores user preferences here
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 1 year
GPS, PREF, VISITOR_INFO1_LIVE, YSC
Cotswold Outdoor
These cookies ensure that our website functions correctly. We keep track of which articles you put in your shopping cart and which products you put on your wish-list
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 1 year.
We do not share your information with third parties
language, access_token, cookiesAccepted, basket_token, wishlist_token, customerID, aff_dedup, aff_cf,
Analytical Cookies
We use analytical cookies to better understand how you use our website and what can be improved. This data helps us to identify issues and to develop user-friendly designs and tools. We can also test the effectiveness of our website. In addition, these cookies provide insights that are useful in advertising analysis.
Name
Target
Properties
Cookie Name
AppNexus
These cookies measure clicks to this website in order to optimize advertising campaigns.
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 90 days.
AppNexus does not share anonymous data with third parties.
anj, sess, uuid2
Google Analytics
With Google Analytics we measure how you use our webshop and how you found us. We use this knowledge to improve our sites. Without these cookies, we will miss your data.
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 2 years.
Google does not share anonymous data with third parties.
utma, utmb, utmc, utmv and utmz, _ga, _gat, _gid
Improve Digital / 360Yield
These cookies measure clicks to our website in order to optimize advertising campaigns.
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 90 days.
tuuid, tuuid_last_update
Reevoo
These cookies are used by Reevoo's Google Analytics integration to reflect generic trends.
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 2 years.
reevoo__utma, reevoo__utmb, reevoo__utmc, reevoo__utmz, reevoo_sp_id.3c95, reevoo_sp_ses.3c95, reevoomark_marker, sp
Sanoma Adapt
These cookies measure clicks to our website in order to optimize advertising campaigns.
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 2 years.
ServedBy, ih, is, lcai9h, lcri5m, pvt, pxl, tuuid, um, umeh
Marketing Cookies (for personalised advertising)
Cotswold Outdoor and our advertising partners (including social media platforms such as Google, Facebook and Instagram) use marketing cookies that track website activity. This means we can show you personalised and relevant offers, including 'targeted messages on third-party advertising platforms' as described in the privacy statement. If you don't accept this form of tracking, you may still see ads from Cotswold Outdoor randomly on other websites.
Name
Target
Properties
Cookie Name
Certona
With Certona we can make personalized product recommendations based on your order history and browser profile.
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 2 years.
RES_TRACKINGID, RES_SESSIONID, Resonance Segment
Bing
We use this script to be able to make more targeted offers based on behavior.
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 1 year.
MUID, MUIDB, _uetsid
Adobe Media Optimizer
These cookies are used for targeted advertising and to document the effectiveness of each individual advertisement.
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 1 year.
Adobe does not share anonymous data with third parties.
everest_g_v2, everest_session_v2
Adobe Audience Manager
Adobe Audience Manager helps us to create customer profiles that we can use to provide you with more personalized content on our website, among other things.
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 180 days.
Adobe does not share anonymous data with third parties.
Adobe QA, aam_uuid, demdex, dextp, VS _ #### @ AdobeOrg, AMCV _ #### @ AdobeOrg, AMCVS _ #### @ AdobeOrg,
Adobe Target
Adobe Target allows us to perform a / b tests on our site and improve our site based on these results.
The cookie is stored for a maximum of 2 weeks.
Adobe does not share anonymous data with third parties.
mbox
How Cotswold Outdoor Processes Personal Data
Some cookies that we use also process your personal data. More information about how Cotswold Outdoor collects and processes personal data can be found in our privacy policy.
Disclaimer
Any links to external websites are provided for your information. Please note that we cannot be held responsible for the content of external websites.
Change your preferences
Change your cookie preferences
Let us know you agree to cookiesWe use marketing, analytical and functional cookies as well as similar technologies to give you the best experience. Third parties, including social media platforms, often place tracking cookies on our site to show you personalised adverts outside of our website. We store your cookie preferences for two years and you can edit your preferences via ‘manage cookies’ or through the cookie policy at the bottom of every page. For more information, please see our cookie policy. See our cookie policyYes, I acceptManage cookies
